《精灵旅社2》
（梅菲斯和乔纳森 新婚快乐）
Welcome！Welcome！
欢迎！欢迎！
Congrats，Drac.
恭喜 德古
Holy smokes，everybody's here.
天呐 大家都来了
Mr。and Mrs。Loughran，the parents of the groom，and family.
洛克伦夫妇 新郎的父母 携家人出席
- Mom and Dad！- Johnny！
- 爸爸 妈妈！- 约翰尼！
I can't believe you're all here.
真不敢相信你们都来了
Yo，how hot is my date？
我的女伴火不火辣？
So hot。Wow.
火辣爆了
How 'bout how hot mine is？
我的女伴呢？
You got a date？
你带了女伴？
Yeah。She's invisible。That's why you can't see her.
是啊 她隐身了 所以你们看不见她
Oh，right。This is the one from 「Canada」？
是哦 从「加拿大」来的那位？
Wedding's starting.
婚礼开始了
Great.
真棒
True。So true，Marty.
说的太好了 马蒂
Aw。How sweet.
好贴心
Oh，my。Look at you.
天啊 看看你
Oh，my gosh.
我的天呐
Is it everything you wanted，my little poisonberry？
这一切你满意吗 我的小毒果？
Oh，it is，Daddy.
满意 爸爸
Except where's Grandpa Vlad？
不过瓦拉德爷爷在哪里呢？
Honey，your gramps would not have been cool with this.
亲爱的 你爷爷可不会接受这场婚姻
He's old-school.
他很守旧
How do we know？If he could just meet Johnny…
我们怎么知道他接受不了？如果他能见见约翰尼…
He would have eaten him.
他会吃了他的
He's not as enlightened as your hip Daddy.
他跟你的时髦老爸比还是不够开明啊
So，you're really okay with him not being a monster？
那老爸你能接受他只是一个人？
Human，monster，unicorn，as long as you're happy.
管他是人 怪物 还是独角兽 只要你幸福就好
Thanks，Dad.
谢谢 爸爸
∮ And you'll always be my moonlight ∮
∮ 你永远是我皎洁的月光 ∮
∮ But now on wings of love you soar ∮
∮ 如今你乘爱的翅膀翱翔 ∮
∮ Now that you're Johnny's girl ∮
∮ 你已成为约翰尼的妻子 ∮
∮ Johnny's girl ∮
∮ 约翰尼的妻子 ∮
∮ And kind of Daddy's，too ∮
∮ 也是爸爸的乖乖女 ∮
∮ Your mom would be so happy ∮
∮ 你妈妈肯定会很高兴 ∮
∮ 'Cause she always knew ∮
∮ 因为她一直明白 ∮
∮ Love is making room for all the best in you ∮
∮ 爱是在为你们的完美铺路 ∮
（一年以后）
Hey，Dad.
老爸
Oh，hey，guys！
两位好！
Todd，take a break.
托德 休息下
So，what's up？
有事吗？
Mavis was wondering if maybe you wanted to go for a fly.
梅菲斯想问你要不要出去兜兜风
Oh。We haven't done that in forever。Any special reason？
我们好久没兜风了 有什么特别的原因吗？
No special reason at all.
没有啊
Right，Mavey？
对吧 梅菲？
What's his deal？
他打的什么主意？
He's silly.
他在犯傻
It's just a beautiful night，and…
今晚夜色很好啊…
Well，if you don't want to…
当然 如果你不想…
No，no！Are you kidding？
不 不！你在开玩笑吗？
I would eat a bucket of garlic to fly with you.
只要能和你出去飞一圈 让我吃一桶大蒜都行
Oh，honey，look at those fluffy clouds.
宝贝 看那些松软的云团
Remember what we played when you were little？
还记得小时候你和我一起玩的游戏吗？
Hide and Go Seek Sharp Objects？
利器捉迷藏？
Okay。Regular Hide and Go Seek.
好吧 正常的捉迷藏啊
Where are you？
你在哪里？
Honeybat！
宝贝蝙蝠！
Mavey！
梅菲！
Honeybat！
宝贝蝙蝠！
I'm gonna get you.
我会抓到你的
Honey？Are you okay？
宝贝？你还好吧？
Yes。It's just a little harder
没事 只是我怀孕了以后
to catch my breath since I'm pregnant.
就经常喘不上气来
Yes，well，I guess that would make it more…
是哦 我想那样确实会…
What？
什么？
I'm gonna be a grandpa！
我要当外公了！
And I'm gonna be a dad！
我要当爸爸了！
∮ 'Cause you're Daddy's girl，or boy ∮
∮ 你是爸爸的女儿 还是儿子 ∮
∮ Daddy's girl，or boy ∮
∮ 女儿 还是儿子 ∮
I'm hungry again，honey.
亲爱的 我又饿了
Can you get me some ice cream with anchovies？
能帮我去弄点凤尾鱼冰激凌吗？
No，no，no。You mustn't give in to your cravings.
不行 你可不能随便吃了
It's not good for the baby.
那对宝宝不好
You need to increase your spider intake，
你要多吃点蜘蛛
so he'll be able to climb ceilings properly.
这样他才能爬上天花板
And eat lots of sheep bile.
还要多喝点羊胆汁
I love you，Dad，but we don't even know
我爱你 爸爸 可是我们还不知道
if the kid's gonna be a vampire.
宝宝会不会是吸血鬼
I'd be thrilled if the baby's human-y，just like Johnny.
如果宝宝和约翰尼一样是普通人 我会很开心的
「Human-y.」 With thousands of years of Dracula genes.
「普通人」 宝宝可有着千年的德古拉基因
Not gonna happen.
绝对不可能是普通人的
As long as the baby's healthy.
只要宝宝健康就好
Of course。A healthy little vampire.
当然 健康的小吸血鬼
Or human.
或是人类
Yes，a human who can fly as a bat.
是的 一个能像蝙蝠一样飞翔的人类
Here。Just have some monster ball soup.
来点怪物球汤吧
It's your mommy's recipe.
这是你妈妈的食谱哦
Thank you，Dad.
谢谢 爸爸
Just like you made it when I was a kid。My favorite.
就像小时候你给我做的一样 我最喜欢了
Sorry.
不好意思
（产房）
Sir，only the father is allowed in the delivery room.
先生 只有孩子的生父才能进入产房
Really？I mean，okay.
是吗？我是说 好吧
He's the family，I guess.
他算是家人了
Oh，look！It's a boy！It's a boy！
快看！是个男孩！男孩！
The Dracula bloodline carries on！
德古拉的血脉得以延续了！
No one will ever harm you as long as I'm here，
只要有我在 没人能伤害你
my little devil dog.
我的小魔孙
Dad，can I hold my baby？
爸 我能抱抱孩子吗？
If I were Dad，I'd say yes.
如果我是你爸 我同意
But I'm the nurse，Francine.
可我是弗朗辛护士啊
Here you go anyway.
还是给你吧
My bad.
我错了
Little Dennis is a year old now。Wow！
丹尼斯现在一岁了
Nice。Yeah。Cute kid.
干得漂亮 萌娃
Okay，time for presents，guys.
好了 礼物时间到 伙伴们
All right！Let's do this boy up！
是时候让这小子大吃一惊了！
Check out what I got him。Bling！
看看我送的 超闪吧！
Wow。Is it cursed？
受过诅咒的？
Super cursed。Only the best.
超级受诅咒的 我只送最好的
Straight from the crypt.
古墓直邮的
He's just starting to walk，so maybe it's heavier than…
他才刚会走路 那链子是不是有点重…
Oh。You're okay，Denisovich.
你没事的 丹尼索维奇
His name is Dennis。Named after my father.
他的名字是丹尼斯 取的是我父亲的名字
It's not his vampire name.
这可不是他的吸血鬼名字
My little Denisovichy-Weesovichy.
我的小丹尼索维奇-维索维奇
Huh！Are we sure he's a vampire？
你确定他就是个吸血鬼？
I mean，not that it's a bad thing，
我并不是说那是什么坏事
but shouldn't he have fangs and that pasty skin you guys have？
只是难道他不应该有和你们一样的尖牙和苍白肤色吗？
Technically，you have until you're five
理论上 你得等到五岁
to get your vampire fangs.
才会长出吸血鬼尖牙
Oh，he'll get his fangs。He's a Dracula.
放心 他会长的 他可是德古拉家的
He's also half Loughran.
他也有一半的洛克伦血统
Maybe he'd be better off where we live.
也许他去我们那里生活会更好
There's more humans there.
那里的人类更多
What？Look how well he's playing with the wolf pups.
什么？看看他和小狼崽们玩得多开心
We have a present。I hope it's acceptable.
我们也准备了礼物 希望你能收下
「My First Guillotine.」
「我的第一个断头台」
Very educational。Well played，Frank.
很有教育意义 送得好 弗兰克
It's great。Thank you。We just have to baby-proof that.
很棒 谢谢 不过我们要加点儿童防护
Johnny，do you know where you put the rubber guards？
约翰尼 你把橡胶防护放哪里了？
Baby-proofing a guillotine？
给断头台加装儿童防护？
So you cut your finger off。It's part of the fun.
大不了把手指切了 也是这游戏的乐趣所在啊
She made me baby-proof the whole hotel.
她让我给整个旅社都装了儿童防护
Someone's overprotective.
某人保护欲太强了
Johnny！Come quick！
约翰尼！快来！
What's up？He's okay？
怎么啦？他没事吧？
Dennis said his first word！
丹尼斯刚说了第一个词！
He did？
真的吗？
Come on，honey。Say it again.
再来 宝贝 再说一次
Bleh，bleh-bleh.
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
I don't say，「Bleh，bleh-bleh.」
我不会说 「巴拉 巴拉巴拉」
We didn't say you did.
我们没说这是你教的
Then where did he get that？
那他从哪里学的？
Bleh，bleh-bleh.
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
Well，maybe sometimes you say it.
也许你这么说过
I only say it when I say I don't say it！
我只是形容我不会说这个的时候才会说！
Bleh，bleh-bleh.
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
Okay，kid。We get it。You can talk.
好啦 小屁孩 我们知道你会说话了
Denisovich.
丹尼索维奇
Dad.
爸爸
Just checking for cavities.
看看有没有蛀牙而已
Bleh，bleh-bleh.
巴拉 巴拉巴拉
It was you！
是你教的！
Oh，my goodness，Leonard.
我的天呐 莱纳德
If you really looked that hideous，
如果你真丑成这样
I don't think I could hang out with you.
我真没法和你一起玩耍了
Guys，what's the deal？
伙计们 搞什么呢？
Is this a party？Pick up a phone.
在开派对啊？快接电话
I don't care if Johnny said it's a 「cool app.」
我才不管约翰尼有没有说过这是个「酷应用」
Johnny's still new here.
他在这里还是个新人
Now，Porridge Head，did you call a hearse for the Gremlinbergs？
好了 浆糊脑袋 你有给格姆林伯格订灵车吗？
No，you're checking your Facebook page。Again.
并没有 你又在看脸书主页了
Drac，I told the guys social media
德古 我和大家说了社交媒体
is the best way to promote the hotel.
是宣传旅社的最佳方式
Right，Clifton？
对吗 克利夫顿？
So，Drac，I wanted to go through some thoughts I had，
德古 作为你新上任的人类关系公关助手
as your new human relations coordinating co-assistant.
我有些想法要和你谈谈
Sure。It's a real job.
这确实是一份真实的工作
Not a cheap excuse to keep Mavis happy，so you never leave here.
而不是用来哄梅菲斯开心 好让你永远待在这里的烂借口
Right。So，I was thinking，
好吧 我的想法是
since we have so many humans now，maybe update some of the acts？
既然我们有了很多人类房客 也许我们应该更新某些表演的内容
Like，maybe the magician？
比如 请个人类魔术师
What's wrong with Harry Three-Eye？
三眼哈利哪里不好了？
Well，he might be a little old-school for the humans.
对人类来说 他有点老派了
Tell me，sir，what was your card？
告诉我 先生 你的牌是什么？
The three of spades？
黑桃三？
Is this your card，my friend？
这是你的牌吗 朋友？
No，Harry's great.
不行 哈利很好
Can't blame Harry for the crowd not being hip.
观众跟不上潮流不能怪哈利
Okay，what about Wayne？
好吧 那韦恩呢？
Wayne？Are you nuts？He's my boy.
韦恩？你疯了吗？他是我铁哥们
Then maybe something other than tennis？
那除了网球 让他干点别的吧？
Okay，so，what you wanna do
好了 你要做的是
is lift the racket right on impact，
击球瞬间向上挥动球拍
so you get that nice top spin.
这样就能打出漂亮的上旋球
Try and hit one.
打一个试试
What is that？What's the noise？It's on me！
怎么回事？这是什么声音？这声音出在我身上！
It's just the cell phone I got you.
是我给你买的手机
Clifton's sending you a text
克利夫顿给你发了短信
so you can practice how to write back.
你要学着怎么回短信
What the… It's not doing it.
什么鬼… 完全没反应
I got it.
我来吧
Dear Drac，gar ugha gjergh arggh grgrgrhgr
亲爱的德古 嘎嘎啦呢嘎啦嘎啦
Now you can text Clifton.
现在你可以给他回短信了
All right，fine.
好吧 好吧
How do you do this？
这个怎么弄啊？
Maybe it's your fingernails.
可能你的指甲太长了
It's easy。Look。I'll text Mavis.
很简单 你看 我来给梅菲斯发短信
Psyched for date night.
约会之夜望眼欲穿
See？And now look，she texted right back.
简单吧？看 她回我了
Gotta cancel。Can't leave Dennis.
得取消了 不能丢下丹尼斯
Okay.
好吧
Are we never allowed to be alone again？
我们难道再也不能独处了吗？
I need to feel loved，too.
我也需要你的爱
And send.
发送
Okay。All that taught me is that you're pathetic.
够了 我唯一看出的就是你很可怜
Yeah，got it。Maybe you should just get Bluetooth.
好吧 也许你该弄个蓝牙
Okay。Blue Tooth，come over here.
好的 蓝牙 过来
So，now what？
然后呢？
Rise and shine，my Denisovich.
太阳晒屁股了 我的丹尼索维奇
Hi，Papa.
早安 外公
Hello，my little devil。Did you have sweet nightmares？
早啊 我的小恶魔 昨晚做了美美的噩梦吗？
Uh-huh。I dreamed that I saw a stegosaurus.
嗯 我梦见我看到一只剑龙
Oh… And were you drinking his blood？
你喝了它的血吗？
No.
没有
Just throwing it out there.
我就是问问而已
Hey！You want to do something cool？
想做点很酷的事情吗？
Yeah！
想啊！
I'm going to teach you how to turn into a bat。Like me.
我要教你怎么变成一只蝙蝠 像我一样
- See？- Cool.
- 看到了吗？- 酷
Yes！Cool，like I said.
对！很酷 就像我说的那样
Now you try.
你来试试
I'm a bat.
我是只蝙蝠
I'm a bat。I'm a bat。I'm a bat.
我是只蝙蝠 我是只蝙蝠 我是只蝙蝠
I'm a bat.
我是只蝙蝠
I mean，a real bat.
我是说 一只真正的蝙蝠
I'm a bat！
我是只蝙蝠！
Denisovich。Take a breath。You can really turn into a bat.
丹尼索维奇 深吸口气 你就真的可以变成一只蝙蝠
Try。Feel the bat.
试试看 想象蝙蝠的样子
Not a chicken.
不是鸡
What's that？The electric boogaloo？
那是什么？机械舞吗？
If I show you I can bust a move，will you try to fly，then？
如果我给你秀下我的舞步 你会试着飞飞看吗？
Dad？Why are you guys dancing？
爸爸？你们为什么在跳舞啊？
Uh，he was sleep-dancing.
他在梦游跳舞
Come on，sweetie。Back to bed.
快 宝贝 回去睡觉
「Back to bed」？It's already after 8：00 p.m.
「回去睡觉」？已经过了晚上八点啦
Don't you remember the new sleep schedule？
你忘记新的睡眠时间计划表了吗？
He's going to human classes half the day.
他要去上人类的班级上半天课
If he could just sleep till 2：00 A.M。tonight，
如果今晚他能睡到半夜两点
it'd be so great for him.
那对他最好不过了
But，honeydeath，six of Wayne's wolf pups
但是 宝贝 韦恩的六只狼宝宝
are having a birthday party tonight.
今晚要开生日派对
You wouldn't want him to miss that.
你不希望他错过吧
Dad，I love the wolf pups，
爸爸 我很爱狼宝宝
but they're a little too rough for Dennis.
但是它们对丹尼斯有点太粗野了
「Too rough」？
「太粗野了」？
Haven't you noticed？Dennis is different.
你没注意到吗？丹尼斯有些与众不同
What are you saying？Denisovich shouldn't be around monsters？
你在说什么？丹尼索维奇不该待在怪物身边？
I love monsters！Video！Video！
我爱怪物！电影！电影！
Oh，you wanna show Papa Drac your monster video？
你想给德古外公看你的怪物电影吗？
Yeah！
没错！
Who's the coolest monster？
谁是最酷的怪物？
Kakie！
凯蒂！
Wee！Kakie one happy monster！
凯蒂是一只快乐的怪物！
Kakie love cake！Yummy！
凯蒂喜欢蛋糕！真好吃！
Tummy get a tummyache.
肚肚疼
Whoa，whoa，whoa。How is that a monster？
那怎么能叫做怪物？
Have some cake，Wuzzlelumplebum.
来点蛋糕吧 维兹
Remember，kids，a real monster always shares.
记住 孩子们 真正的怪物总是懂得分享
「Shares」？Yes！When I think monsters，I think 「shares.」
「分享」？对！我一想到怪物 就会想到「分享」
Now，let me tell you what a real monster is，Denisovich.
好了 我来告诉你什么才是真正的怪物吧 丹尼索维奇
Dad，please。He's practically five already。Don't force it.
爸爸 拜托 他已经五岁了 别强迫他了
Slow down，Wuzzlelumplebum.
慢点吃 维兹
∮ Twinkle，twinkle，little star How I wonder ∮
∮ 一闪 一闪 亮晶晶 满天都是 ∮
Mommy，I'm too old for lullabies.
妈妈 我已经长大了 不听摇篮曲了
What？That's not how that one goes.
什么？不应该是那样唱的
This is the way most people sing it.
大多数人都是这么唱的
「Most people」？What's wrong with…
「大多数人」？那这样呢…
∮ Suffer，suffer，scream in pain ∮
∮ 忍受 忍受 尖叫与痛苦 ∮
∮ Blood is spilling from your brain ∮
∮ 血从你脑中喷出 ∮
- Daddy。- Come on。You know how I sang it to you.
- 爸爸 - 拜托 你知道我是怎么对你唱的
∮ Zombies gnaw you like a plum ∮
∮ 丧尸如李子般将你啃光 ∮
∮ Piercing cries and you succumb ∮
∮ 尖厉地哭吧你只有投降 ∮
∮ Suffer，suffer，scream in pain ∮
∮ 忍受 忍受 尖叫与痛苦 ∮
∮ You will never breathe again ∮
∮ 你再也不能喘气了 ∮
Still works.
照样有用
（生日快乐）
Happy birthday，Wally，Wilson，
生日快乐 沃利 威尔森
Whoopi，Waylon，Weepy and Wanye.
乌碧 韦伦 威皮 还有 万耶
Denisovich！My big boy！You made it！
丹尼索维奇！我的乖孩子！你来了！
I thought about what you said，Dad.
我考虑了一下你说的话 爸爸
Maybe I was being a little overprotective.
可能我确实对他有点过于保护了
Thank you，coffin cake.
谢谢你 我的棺材蛋糕宝贝
Dennis！I love you！Zing！
丹尼斯！我爱你！
Hi，Winnie.
你好 温妮
I just love your yummy strawberry locks！Zing，zing！
我很爱吃你美味的草莓锁！
Winnie。Give him his space，hon。I'm sorry，Mavis.
温妮 别那么黏着他 亲爱的 我很抱歉 梅菲斯
It's okay，Aunt Wanda。They're just playing.
没关系 旺达阿姨 他们只是在玩
Holy rabies！Limbo？I used to love that game！
我的老天狗啊！地狱边境？我以前很喜欢那个游戏！
Get in there，Mavey.
去玩吧 梅菲
Really？But I'm a parent now.
真的吗？但是我现在是个母亲了
Show 'em how it's done.
给他们展示一下怎么玩的
Okay。Okay，okay.
好 好 好吧
No way！A pinata？
不会吧！彩糖罐？
Oh，Mavis，honey。That's for later.
梅菲斯 亲爱的 等一会才能砸那个
We don't want the pups to have too much…
我们不想这些宝宝们摄入过多的…
Candy！
糖果！
Sugar.
糖分
I'm sorry。Did I start all that？
对不起 是我挑起的吗？
Don't worry。There's a reason they call it a litter.
别担心 它们不是平白无故被叫做一窝幼崽的
Dennis！Are you okay？
丹尼斯！你没事吧？
I got a candy.
我拿到了一颗糖
Look！Your tooth came out.
看啊！你的牙掉了
Are you kidding me？He got his tooth knocked out？
你在开玩笑吗？他的牙被磕掉了？
Oh，yes，indeed。Here comes the fang.
确实 尖牙就要长出来咯
Dad。His baby tooth wasn't a fang。Why would this one be？
爸爸 他的小奶牙才不是尖牙呢 为什么这颗牙会是尖牙啊
He's not a monster.
他又不是一只怪物
The sun's gonna come out soon，and we gotta get to his classes.
太阳快出来了 我们得带他上课去了
What's wrong with the classes we have here？Like the kids' yoga？
我们这里的课程有什么问题吗？比如说儿童瑜伽？
Yoga！
瑜伽！
This is Denisovich's home.
这里是丹尼索维奇的家
I don't know，Dad.
我不知道 爸爸
What don't you know？
你不知道什么？
Well，we've been talking about moving.
我们一直在讨论搬到
Somewhere safer for Dennis.
一个对于丹尼斯更加安全的地方去
Maybe where Johnny grew up in California.
或许约翰尼在加州长大的地方就不错
I'm sorry，but you can't just make somebody something they're not.
对不起 但是你不能硬把某人变成他不属于的种类
Come on，honey。We have to go.
快 宝贝 我们得走了
Mavey，wait。You can't mean that.
梅菲 等等 你不是说真的吧
You're in on this？The leaving？
你也同意了？搬家的事？
Uh… It's not definite at all.
现在还不确定呢
It's just something she's definitely talking about，
她还只是说说
but until we do it，it's not definitized.
但是我们去实施之前 那都不能叫绝对
Did he just cover me with birdseed？
他是不是用鸟食把我裹起来了？
Yeah，he covered me.
没错 他把我裹起来了
Dad，it's not a fang.
爸爸 那不是一颗尖牙
Dad，I don't know if it's the right place for Dennis.
爸爸 我不知道这对于丹尼斯来说是不是一个好地方
Right，Johnny？
没错吧 约翰尼？
Oh，hey，dudeman。It's not me。It's Mavey.
老兄 不是我说的 都是梅菲的主意
Hey，dudeman。I'm afraid to say anything.
老兄 我什么话都不敢说
Hey，dudeman。I'm a dudeman！
老兄 我是个老兄！
Uh，Drac？Who you talkin' to？
德古？你在跟谁说话？
Do not disturb。The count's wiggin' out in here.
闲人勿扰 伯爵正在这里发疯呢
What are you wiggin' out about，Drac？
你发什么疯呢 德古？
The kids。Mavey Wavey's saying she wants to leave.
是因为孩子们 雪雁梅菲说她想离开这里
She wants to leave？What about Johnny？He doesn't wanna go.
她想离开？那约翰尼呢？他不想走
He's making the hotel more human-y for Dennis.
他为了丹尼斯正在把旅社变得更加人性化
You know，seeing that he isn't a monster.
因为他不是一只怪物
He is a monster！
他是只怪物！
He's just a late fanger.
他只是尖牙长得晚而已
And I could be a hand model.
我可以当个手模
Shut up！It's all that human-y stuff
闭嘴！都是那套人类的东西
that's confusing poor Denisovich.
让可怜的丹尼索维奇感到很困惑
So maybe you gotta get the kid
所以也许你得让孩子
around more monster-y things。Ooh！
多接触一些怪物的东西
Oh，I need a cape.
我需要一件斗篷
I can't。She's always around，checking up on me.
我做不到 她一直在身边 盯着我
Man，if you could just get some alone time.
如果你要能跟他多独处一段时间
Wait a minute。That's what Johnny wants，too.
等等 约翰尼也想这样
Alone time with Mavis.
他想多与梅菲斯独处一会
Have they even had a vacation
他们结婚之后
since before they were married？
度过假吗？
They're going to now。And so are we。Frank，you're a genius.
他们马上就要去度假了 我们也是 弗兰克 你真是个天才
We'll take Denisovich to all our old haunts.
我们把丹尼索维奇带到我们的老宅子去
Each of us will show him our skills.
我们每个人都教他各自的技能
Teach him how to be a monster.
教他如何变成一个怪物
And he'll be fanging it up in no time.
他很快就会长出尖牙
Boy turns five next week.
这孩子下周就五岁了
If he's not a vampire by his birthday，it ain't happenin'.
如果他到生日之前还变不成吸血鬼 他就再也不会成为吸血鬼了
Oh，it ain't ain't happening，baby.
不会的 宝贝
All he needs is time with his vampa.
他需要的仅仅是与他吸公相处的时间
「Vampa」？
「吸公」？
Vampire grandpa.
吸血鬼外公
Come on，man。That's obvious.
拜托 这都听不懂吗
Johnny。Come outside.
约翰尼 出来一下
What？Who is it？
谁啊？
It's your father-in-law。I need to talk to you.
你的岳父 我有话对你说
What's up？
什么事？
Let me get rid of them。Sorry.
我这就把它们赶走 抱歉
No problem-o。I was kinda diggin' the attention.
没关系哟 我有点喜欢这种被关注感觉
Can they stay？I don't think they're ready to leave yet.
可以让它们待在这里吗？我觉得它们现在还离不开这里呢
Come on。Go to your mother.
快去 去找你们妈妈
Look，you want to stay here，right？
听着 你想待在这里对吧？
Of course.
当然
This is the first place where I can really be myself.
这是第一个我可以真正做回自己的地方
I haven't felt this alive
酥边匹萨问世之后
since they invented stuffed-crust pizza.
我就再没有感到如此鲜活了
Well，then，we've got some work to do。Okay，so here's the plan.
那么 我们就有些事情要做了 计划是这样的
Maybe it's a good idea to take her to your hometown.
可能把她带到你的故乡是个好主意
But remember…
但是记住…
So，it's sliced avocado，rolled oats with apricot，
要吃牛油果片 杏肉燕麦卷
the Aveeno moisturizer after every bath.
每次沐浴后要用阿维诺保湿霜
- And… - Then the shea butter on his tush before his PJs
- 还有… - 给他穿睡衣前在他犬齿上抹酪脂油
and then 20 minutes with the nebulizer
还有就是给他读知识工厂有声小说时
while I read his Learning Factory Phonics book to him.
给他喷雾二十分钟
It's asking a lot，Dad。We could just take Dennis with us.
这会很麻烦的 爸爸 我们带着丹尼斯就好了
What？Are you kidding me？And get him off his routine？
什么？你在开玩笑吗？要打乱他的日常生活节奏吗？
No，no，no.
不行
You kids go to California，
孩子们你们去加州
and see if it's the right place to raise Denisovich.
看看那里适不适合养育丹尼索维奇
And you remember how to video chat？
你记得如何视频聊天吧？
Yes，yes。With the phone and the buttons and the agony.
记得 痛苦地用那个按钮和电话聊
Thanks for being so understanding，Dad.
谢谢你这么善解人意 爸爸
I know you'll keep him safe.
我知道你会保证他的安全的
Of course，Mavey。Stake my heart and hope to die.
当然了 梅菲 我发誓
I'm just gonna miss him so much.
我会很想他的
I love you，Dennis.
我爱你 丹尼斯
I love you，Mommy.
我也爱你 妈咪
I'll tell him Mavey Wavey stories every night before bed.
我每天晚上睡前都会给他讲雪雁梅菲的故事
You're the best。I love you，Dad.
你真是太好了 我爱你 爸爸
Gonna miss all you guys。You're all my family.
我会想你们大家的 你们都是我的家人
Love you，Drac.
爱你 德古
Yes。I love you，too.
我也爱你
Now，remember the plan。Just keep her distracted and happy.
别忘了我们的计划 只要引开她的注意力 让她开开心心的就好
- But not too happy，capisce？- Got it.
- 但也别太开心了 明白吗？- 知道了
Operation 「Just Keep Her Distracted and Happy，
行动 「引开她的注意力 让她开开心心」
「But Not Too Happy，Capisce，」 starts now。Cool？
「但也别太开心了 明白吗」 现在开始 怎么样？
Smiling on the outside.
保持微笑
Will you hug my backpack？
你会拥抱我的背包吗？
No.
不会
Back to bed.
睡觉觉
Ah，yes，we'll get to the bed。We all love the bed.
对 我们会去睡觉觉 我们都爱睡觉觉
But we're just gonna do one thing first.
但是我们要先做一件事
Is it shorts weather where we're going？
我们去的地方现在是穿短裤的天气吗？
Jeez。I hope not。My body isn't swimsuit-ready yet.
天啊 但愿不是 我的身体还没做好穿泳装的准备呢
Whatever。Where's Griffin？
无所谓了 格里芬呢？
Hey，can I have a second？I'm just saying goodbye to Emily.
能等我一会吗？我正跟艾米丽道别呢
Oh，brother.
天啊
I'm gonna miss you so much.
我会特别想你的
You know，you have to be strong，honey.
你知道的 你必须坚强 宝贝
Because what we have is unbreakable.
因为我们的感情是坚不可摧的
Babe，don't cry。Everyone's looking.
宝贝 别哭嘛 大伙儿都看着呢
Okay，I gotta call him on this.
不行 我必须让他摊牌
Just let him play it out，get it over with.
就让他演吧 赶紧演完算了
Okay，you two lovebirds.
好了 你们两个小恋人
Drink your champagne and let's get going.
喝完香槟我们就要出发了
Oh，yeah。No，sure。Okay.
当然 好吧
Cheers，babe.
干杯 宝贝
Oh。You klutz.
看你笨手笨脚的
We can't say nothin' about this？
我们啥也不许说？
No。We don't have time for zingers.
对 没时间跟他斗嘴
How do you click in the stupid car seat？
这破安全带怎么系啊？
You gotta cut those nails，man.
你该剪指甲了 哥们
We just strap our kids down with duct tape.
我们一般用胶带把孩子们绑好
What's he doing here？
他来干嘛？
I told him he could come。He's never been outside the hotel.
是我说他可以来的 他从没出过旅社一步
Blobby，there's no room。Sorry，man.
布罗比 没地方了 不好意思啊
Yeah，that ain't happenin'.
还真是没想到呢
Fine，put him on the Rascal。Let's just get going.
好吧 让他骑小摩托 赶紧出发吧
Where are we going，Papa Drac？
我们去哪里啊 德古外公
Oh，Denisovich，we're going to have an adventure.
丹尼索维奇 我们要去冒险
A monster-y adventure.
怪物冒险
Yay！Monsters！We're gonna eat cake.
怪物！我们要吃蛋糕了
What did he say？
他说啥？
No。No cake on this monster trip.
不 这次怪物之旅没有蛋糕
No cake，cebause Kakie says，「Too much cake makes tummy ache.」
没有蛋糕 应为凯蒂说 「蛋糕吃多了肚子疼」
「A monster always shares.」
「怪物就要分享」
We may need more than a week.
一个星期可能不够啊
Hey，you know who could fix the kid in a snap？Vlad.
你知道谁能轻松治好这个孩子吗？瓦拉德
What？We don't need to call Vlad。We got this.
什么？不需要叫瓦拉德 我们能行
You see，Denisovich，monsters are nice，just like you.
你看啊 丹尼索维奇 怪物们很友好 就跟你一样
But when the moon comes out，the real monster fun begins.
但当月亮出来后 真正的怪物派对才开始
Being scary。Right，guys？
恐怖得很 对吧 各位？
Guys？Guys！What is wrong with you？
各位？你们！你们有毛病吗？
Come on。Everybody likes that song.
拜托 所有人都喜欢这首歌啊
We're not everybody。We're scary monsters。Remember？
我们可不是一般人 我们是可怕的怪物 记得吗？
Hey，what are you putting in？
你要播放什么？
It's an audio book.
是本有声书
Bigfoot's life story。He reads it himself.
大脚怪的一生 他亲自口述的
Chapter One.
第一章
This is gonna be so amazing.
这次旅行一定会很棒的
Oh，yeah。You're gonna be so happy，but not too happy.
当然了 你会很开心的 但也不能太过开心
- Huh？- What？
- 你说什么？- 什么？
I wanna see everything you did growing up.
我想看你从小到大做过的一切
As long as you're distracted，capisce？
只要能分散你注意力就行 懂吗？
We can hit a few spots on the way to my parents.
我们在去我父母家的路上可以停几个地方
Lemme just quickly call home.
我先给家里打个电话
Ah！Don't do that.
别打
It's only 1：00 A.M。there。Dennis isn't even up yet.
那里才凌晨一点 丹尼斯还没醒呢
Right。I'm just not used to being away from him.
对哦 我就是不太习惯跟他分开
Everything's gonna be cool。Your dad was so all over it.
不会有事的 一切都有你爸呢
I know。He's the best.
我知道 他最好了
Right turn，here.
这里右转
Denisovich，rise and shine.
丹尼索维奇 起来嗨啊
Boys，this bringing back any memories？
几位 对这里还有印象吗？
We used to prowl around here when we were in our 100s.
我们一百多岁的时候经常在这里玩耍
The Dark Forest of Slobozia.
斯洛博齐亚的黑暗森林
（黑暗森林市政公园 自行车道）
Nice how they built it up.
看现在这社区多和谐
Okay，out of the car.
好了 下车
Denisovich，you're going to see
丹尼索维奇 你会看到
every monster do his specialty.
怪物们各施其才
First，Frank's gonna show us how he scares people.
首先 弗兰克将表演如何恐吓人类
Yay！He's gonna say，「Boo.」
他会说 「嘭」
Yeah，I don't think 「boos」 ever work.
「嘭」根本吓不到人
But that's why we're here。To learn from the master.
但这就是我们来的原因 向大师学习
Okay，I'll give it a shot.
好吧 我可以试试
Yeah，guess it just depends on work.
应该是要努力才行吧
Frankenstein！
弗兰肯斯坦！
Hey，how ya doin'？
你好吗？
You're awesome！Can we take a picture？Is that okay？
你太酷了！我们能合影吗？可以吗？
Sure，okay。Little selfie action.
当然 来个小自拍
For real？
不是吧？
Awesome！Thank you so much.
太棒了！非常感谢
Hey，have a great day.
祝你们今天愉快
Oh。He's adorable。He's adorable.
他好可爱 他好可爱
Adorable，yes.
可爱 是的
Not scary，but 「boo」 is a start.
不可怕 但「嘭」也算个开始了
My birthday cake's gonna have the coolest guy on it.
我的生日蛋糕要放最帅的人在上面
Let me guess。Kakie.
我猜猜啊 凯蒂
No。He's so cool。He climbs walls and wears a cape.
不 那个人非常酷 他会爬墙还穿着披风
Oh，really。And who is this very cool guy？
真的哦 那这个非常帅的人是谁啊？
Batman！
蝙蝠侠！
Batman。Great.
蝙蝠侠 好吧
You don't know anyone else with a cape that's cool？
你难道不认识其他穿披风的帅哥吗？
This is good。Stop here.
这里好 停车
Okay，Wayne。It's your turn。Go kill something.
好了 韦恩 该你了 开杀吧
Denisovich，watch this.
丹尼索维奇 看好了
What？
什么？
I told you，come on.
我们说过的 快
If we don't inspire Denisovich，
如果我们不启发丹尼索维奇
how's he going to find his inner monster？
他怎么发现内心的怪物？
Who's in a monster？
谁在怪物里面？
Nobody，just…
没谁 就是…
Here，have an avocado.
给 吃个牛油果吧
Your mommy says it's a good fat.
你妈说它是很好的脂质来源
Whatever the heaven that means.
谁知道说的是啥
Listen，I'm not gonna set monsters back again
听着 我不会再变成怪物
just to make your grandkid like vampires.
就为了让你孙子喜欢吸血鬼
Anyway，there's nothing to kill here。It's all been…
再说了 这里没什么活物啊 都已经…
What a cutie.
好可爱吖
But kill him.
不过你得去杀了他
Oh，great。You know I haven't done this in years.
真是的 你知道我多年不杀生了
We don't need to kill anymore。We have Pop-Tarts.
现在不需要杀戮了 我们有果馅饼干
Denisovich，you're going to love this.
丹尼索维奇 你肯定会喜欢的
Wayne's going to eat that whole deer，and the next one's yours.
韦恩要吞下那整头鹿 下一个交给你来
Wayne，go.
韦恩 上吧
Oh，man。I'm too old for this.
天啊 我都一把老骨头了
Okay，how's it go again？
好吧 怎么做的来着？
No，no，wait。That's for the moon.
不 月亮出来的时候才要这么叫
Oh，I growl。Right，here goes.
我该咆哮 好的 来吧
Growl！
咆哮！
Get it，boy.
捡回来 乖乖
Get it，Uncle Wayne.
快抢啊 韦恩叔叔
Some werewolf。Did you actually say the word 「growl？」
好个狼人 你还真把「咆哮」说出来了啊？
You're a werewussy.
你是个狼鳖才对
I said I was rusty.
我都说宝刀已老了
Gimme me that Frisbee.
把飞盘给我
No！It's my Frisbee！I fetched it！
不！这是我的飞盘！我接到的！
Give it to me！Give it back！
给我！给我！
Give it over here！Give me that！Give it back！
拿过来！松口！松口！
He's fine。He's Blobby.
他没事的 他可是布罗比
This place is so amazing and scenic.
这个地方好棒好美啊
What do you wanna show me first？
我们先看什么？
Mmm。I don't know.
我也不知道
It's pretty，but there's really
这里是很漂亮 但天黑后
nothing to do once it gets dark.
就真没什么好做的了
Wait。What's that place？
停车 那是什么地方？
So，you're telling me that I can pick
你是说我可以在这么多种
between all these different kinds of chips？
薯片里随便选？
Yes.
对
How do people decide？
这怎么做决定啊？
Now what's that beautiful fountain of rubies？
那漂亮的红宝石喷泉又是什么？
Johnny，have you tried this Slurpee？
约翰尼 你喝过这个思乐冰吗？
Not that quickly，hon.
别太急 亲爱的
It comes in 48 flavors。We have to try them all.
它有四十八种口味 我们都试一遍
Uh，I don't know if we have time.
我们可能时间不够
Why？This place is open all night。Right，sir？
为什么？这地方整夜都开 对吧 先生？
Yes.
是的
Johnny，look.
约翰尼 快看
They're making a TV show about this place and we're the stars.
有人在录这个地方的节目 录的就是我们
Hello，world.
你好啊 世界
Awesome.
好棒
It's totally awesome。You're so lucky，Kal.
棒极了 你真是太幸运了 卡尔
Hello，world.
你好 世界
Okay，Murray。Your turn.
好了 墨瑞 该你了
Excuse us。Do you know where someone can get a bite around here？
抱歉 你知道附近哪里有吃东西的地方吗？
Did you seriously just ask a vampire where to get a bite？
你真的在问一个吸血鬼哪里有吃东西（意同「被咬一口」）的地方吗？
Oh，gosh。I didn't mean… We're not from around here.
天啊 我不是那个意思… 我们不是本地人
This is so embarrassing。Just keep going.
太丢人了 开你的车吧
Sorry to bother you。Love your chocolate cereal.
打扰了啊 特别喜欢你代言的巧克力麦片
So，what do you want me to do now？
那你现在想要我做什么？
Denisovich，you won't believe it.
丹尼索维奇 说出来你都不信
The mummy can crash through walls
木乃伊可以毁掉墙壁
and turn into a swarm of beetles
变成一群甲虫
and put a curse on anyone.
还能诅咒任何人
That sounds mean.
这样不好
It's fun mean。Okay.
但很有趣 好了
So，check it out.
拭目以待吧
Murray's going to conjure up
墨瑞要召唤
the biggest sandstorm you've ever seen.
你有生以来见过的最大的沙尘暴
Hit it！
动手吧！
Sandstorm？It's been awhile.
沙尘暴？我好久不做了
Not my problem。Do it。Say your little spell.
我不管 快点 念你的小咒语
Okay.
好吧
I got this。Frank，Wayne，Griffin，just try not to faint.
我可以的 弗兰克 韦恩 格里芬 别晕倒啊
My back.
我的背
Oh。Wait.
我来
How cute！
好可爱！
Wait。Stop at that playground。Look at these cute kids.
等下 在游乐场停车 看这些孩子多可爱呀
Holy rabies！This looks like a blast.
我的老天狗啊！好像很好玩的样子
I don't know，Mavey.
不好说啊 梅菲
This can be pretty dangerous
你要是技术不好的话
if you don't know what you're doing.
可是非常危险的
Of course，I rock these bikes.
当然了 我可是玩得很溜
May I，little dude？
我能试试吗 小家伙？
Check it out。Oh，yeah.
快看吧
This is how I rolled every summer.
我每年夏天都这么炫酷的
I think I scratched it.
我好像把你车子擦花了
My turn.
该我了
Mavey，I told you，it took me years to get this good.
梅菲 跟你说了 我多年苦练才这么厉害
Well，I'll give it a try.
我试试好了
You feel me now？That's my girlfriend，suckers.
看到了吧？那是我女朋友 衰蛋们
Your wife，Johnny.
是老婆 约翰尼
My wife。Even better.
我老婆 更棒了
That was sick，lady。Where did you learn how to do that stuff？
太厉害了 女士 你从哪里学到的？
Transylvania.
精灵旅社
That's cool。I have a cousin from Pennsylvania.
好厉害 我有个表亲是宾夕法尼亚的
Oh。These little guys are so sweet。Dennis would love them.
这些小家伙们太可爱了 丹尼斯会喜欢他们的
What an awesome place to raise a kid.
这地方多适合养孩子啊
Oh。To raise a kid？
养孩子？
I don't know about awesome.
没那么适合吧
Maybe tubular。Capisce？
也就一般般吧 懂吗？
Anyways，we should hit my folks' place.
总之 我们该去我父母家了
I said we'd be there by now.
我和他们说现在该到了
Sure.
当然
Oh，hey，it's after 3：00 o'clock in Transylvania.
现在精灵旅社过三点了
I'm gonna check on Dennis，okay？
我要问一下丹尼斯的情况 行吗？
Chocolate cereal。Are you kidding me？
巧克力麦片 逗我吗？
It's okay，Drac。It's 'cause they love us.
别在意 德古 他们这是爱我们
Yeah。Monsters are what's goin' on.
对 现在怪物们可火了
Oh，yeah。You should embrace it like I did.
没错 你应该像我一样接受这个事实
I've got a best-selling workout video.
我发布了最畅销的健身视频
Follow me，ladies。Right。And left.
跟我做 女士们 右边 然后左边
No，girls。Watch me。You're not watching.
不 姑娘们 看我 你们根本没在看
Here we go。And eight and seven and six…
加油 八 七 六…
That's not me，guys.
这不是我的风格 各位
Come on，
别这样
even Bigfoot's tearin' it up in the German soccer league.
就连大脚怪都在德国足球联队里大显身手
Oh，no。Oh，no，no，no.
不不不
It's Mavis.
是梅菲斯
You gotta answer it.
你得接电话啊
You're pushing too hard。Lighter.
你按得太用力了 别那么使劲
All right！
好吧！
Denisovich，wake up。Oh，boy，he's out cold.
丹尼索维奇 醒醒 天啊 他睡得太熟了
I got this.
看我的
Dad，what took so long？
爸 怎么这么久才接电话？
What？
什么？
Nothing，Mavey。We're all great here at the hotel.
没什么大不了的 梅菲 我们在旅社里都挺好的
Just doing hotel things.
就做些平常在旅社里做的事
Sorry，can't handle your breath.
对不起 我真受不了你的口臭了
I hear ya.
好啵
How are you？
你那边怎么样？
We're having a blast.
我们玩的超开心
We just went biking and mini-marting。It's so fun here.
去骑了车 还逛了小超市 这里太好玩了
Is Dennis okay？
丹尼斯还好吧？
Oh。Of course.
当然
You want to see him？
你要看看他吗？
Yes。Yes，I do.
好啊 好啊
Hi，baby。How are you？
宝贝 你怎么样啊？
Mommy.
妈妈
I happy.
我 开心
Hey，little dude.
小宝贝
Why is he wearing sunglasses？
他为什么戴着墨镜？
Oh，we were playing.
我们正在玩
It's a superhero thing.
超级英雄之类的游戏
Cebause，I'm Sunglasses Man，to the rescue！
应为 我是墨镜侠 我要拯救世界！
- Okay，take it down a notch。- I'm flying.
- 好了 你不用这么大声的 - 我会飞
You sound funny.
你的声音怪怪的
Oh，no，no，that's his Sunglasses Man voice.
没事 墨镜侠就是用这种声音说话的
Static。The signal is bad。Mavis，are you there？
干扰 可能是信号不好 梅菲斯 你听得见吗？
Yeah，I'm still…
听得见啊 我还…
All right。I guess he's having fun.
算了 他好像玩得挺开心的
Of course he is.
那是肯定的
Wow，I nailed it with the Sunglasses Man.
我演墨镜侠演得真棒
Right off the top of my head.
我的临场发挥能力太强了
I threw in a 「cebause.」 Did everyone see that？
你们听见了没？我还说了「应为」
She said she was having fun。Johnny's blowing it.
她说她玩的很开心 约翰尼全搞砸了
She's biking and mini-marting。She's gonna wanna move！
她骑了车 还逛了小超市 她肯定想赶紧搬过去住！
I gotta fix this kid now。Are we almost there or what？
我得赶快让这个宝贝变过来 我们还要多久才能到？
Okay，I may
好吧 我可能是
have taken a wrong turn a few miles back.
在几英里之前就走错了路
- Don't get mad。- What？
- 别生气 - 什么？
Someone turn on the navigator on this thing.
谁能帮我把这上面的导航打开
Look how light I touch it.
你看看我是怎么轻轻触屏的
Please enter your destination.
请输入您的目的地
Please。I am begging you.
求您了 快点输入吧
Yeah，this is gonna be good，Denisovich.
没错 丹尼索维奇 这里特别适合你
Scary stuff，okay？It's in you.
吓人的东西 知道吗？那是你的天性
We just gotta concentrate on the scary.
我们要做的只是把注意力集中在吓人这件事上
Papa Drac？Do you miss Grandma？
德古外公？你想念外婆吗？
Miss Grandma？Oh。Sure，I do.
你外婆吗？我当然想她
I miss her every day。She was my zing.
我每一天都很想她 她和我是命中注定在一起的
Why do you ask？
你为什么问这个？
I don't know.
我也不知道
Do you miss anybody？
你在想念谁吗？
I miss Mommy and Daddy.
我想爸爸妈妈了
And who else？You miss that Winnie？
别的人呢？你想不想温妮？
The pup who tackles you and tries to lick you all the time？
就是每天都挠你痒痒 还总想舔你的那只小狗？
Yeah，but we're just friends.
也想啊 不过我们只是朋友
Oh，no，no，no。You're a Dracula.
不 你是德古拉家族的人
You can't just be friends
你不可能和温妮那么一个
with a cute，hairy number like Winnie.
可爱的 毛茸茸的小姑娘只做朋友的
Right turn，now！Here。You imbecile！
向右转！就是这里 你个笨蛋！
Oh，right。Turn，Griffin！
没错 右转 格里芬！
Yes，Papa Drac.
遵命 德古外公
Wait and see，fellas.
你们就等着瞧吧
This kid'll be guzzling goat blood in no time.
这孩子很快就会像打了鸡血一样的
You have arrived at your destination。Yes！
您已到达目的地 没错！
- Yes！- Here we are.
- 没错！- 我们到了
It's the vampire summer camp I went to as a kid.
我小时候就来参加过这个专门为吸血鬼小孩设计的夏令营
What's it，Camp Vamp？
那是什么 吸血鬼夏令营吗？
No。Who names their camp 「Camp Vamp？」
才不是呢 谁会起这么难听的名字？
It's Camp Winnepacaca.
是温尼帕卡卡夏令营
You see，Denisovich？
你看 丹尼索维奇？
This is where I learned to catch mice and shapeshift.
我就是在这里学会变形和抓老鼠的
And use my incredible powers and strength.
还有学会了该如何运用我强大的能力和力量
It's pretty cool。Huh？
还挺好玩的 对吧？
Badminton.
羽毛球
Yes，I don't remember this badminting.
好吧 我不记得这里还教这门课了
Well，well，is this a night？How ya doing，folks？
各位好啊 今晚真美 不是吗？
I'm Dana，the director.
我叫德纳 是这里的负责人
We're sure excited to have you legends visitin' us.
各位的到访是我们的荣幸
What can I do you for？
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Well，I'm very interested in
我想让我的外孙丹尼索维奇
sending my grandboy，Denisovich，here.
来这里学习
Oh。This little redheaded，non-fangy little guy？
就是这个红头发 还没长尖牙的小男孩？
Oh，they're in there。He's a late fanger.
他有尖牙的 可能是他发育比较晚
That's why we came here.
所以我们才想到要来这里
Can you show us some of the drills，
你能带我们参观一下吗
like where they catch the mice？
比如看看他们学抓老鼠的地方？
Can do。Of course now we call it Tee-Mousing.
当然 不过我们现在管这项活动叫「领老鼠」
So they don't have to catch the mice？
所以 他们根本不用自己抓老鼠？
Nope。We find this is a good way to build their confidence.
是的 我们认为这样更有助于孩子们建立自信
Come here.
过来啊
It's right there！What's the matter with you？
老鼠就在这里呢！你有什么不敢抓的？
Hokey-pokey.
这就是我们的教学方法
There it is，Denisovich。Where Papa learned to fly.
你看 外公就是在那里学会飞的
Ooh！I wanna fly like Papa.
我想和外公一样能飞起来
Yeah。We're over here，now.
我们现在在这边练习了
Had to scale it down。Insurance.
出于安全考虑 我们不得不降低了难度
Help me。Help me。Help me.
帮帮我 帮帮我
Hokey-pokey。See ya at the campfire.
这就是教学方法啊 我在篝火那边等你们
Well，gosh！Welcome，you two.
天啊！欢迎你们俩回家
Hey，gang.
你们好
Hi，guys。This is so exciting.
你们好啊 我实在是太激动了
Ah！Look at all of this。So cool.
这里的一切都这么棒
Wow！I can't believe I'm actually here.
我简直不敢相信我真的来这里了
Well，you are.
没错 你确实来了
Now，how does it work？Are you up all night and sleep all day？
还适应吗？你是不是要白天睡觉 晚上活动？
Oh。I'll do whatever you guys want.
我怎样都可以 无所谓的
Good.
那就好
- 'Cause I bought this pretty sunhat for you。- Linda.
- 我给你买了这顶美美的遮阳帽 - 琳达
But otherwise this poncho，if you wanna be safe.
不过你要是怕不好看的话 我还准备了这件斗篷
We can deal with it later，Linda.
琳达 我们可以以后再说
Okay.
好吧
Oh！Come see.
对了！快来看看
I've set up your bedroom.
我布置了你们的卧室
It's just like Transylvania.
和精灵旅社好像
Oh，Transylvania。That was a fun experience.
说到精灵旅社 那次玩得太开心了
Mike was afraid he'd get disemboweled and eaten，
麦克担心他会被掏空内脏然后吃掉
but I told him he was just being silly.
不过我告诉他 是他想得太多了
That was you，Linda.
那是你吧 琳达
Oh。There they are.
他们来了
You know，we have a couple of
这附近有几个
mixed families in the neighborhood，
混血家庭
so I thought I'd invite them over.
我觉得应该请他们过来坐坐
They might be nice for you guys to talk to
你们既然想要搬回来住
since you're thinkin' about moving here.
和他们聊聊天应该也不错吧
Hi，Caren。Hi，Pandragora.
你好 卡伦 你好 潘朵哥拉
- Welcome，Mavis。- Hey，guys.
- 欢迎你 梅菲斯 - 你们好
Yeah，you're gonna dig it here。Don't even worry.
你们一定会喜欢这里的 根本不用担心
People are totally cool with our lifestyle choice.
人们完全不会介意我们的生活方式
I mean，the kids get picked on a little，
虽说有时候小孩子会受点欺负
but it toughens them up.
不过这也能让他们变得坚强
Oh，hey，you guys。And this is Loretta.
你们好啊 这位是洛雷塔
She's married to Paul，who's a werewolf.
她嫁给了狼人保罗
Excuse me？
你说什么？
Yes，I was telling Mavis
是啊 我正在给梅菲斯介绍
about the other monster-human couples in town.
这附近其他由人类和怪物组成的家庭
I am not a werewolf.
我不是狼人
Oh。I thought…
我还以为…
Well，you're welcome to stay and have some cupcakes.
好吧 那你也可以坐下来吃点杯子蛋糕嘛
∮ Vampires will be friends forever ∮
∮ 吸血鬼永远是好朋友 ∮
∮ Through the centuries together ∮
∮ 永永远远在一起 ∮
∮ Even in the brightest sunny weather ∮
∮ 即使在阳光灿烂的日子里 ∮
∮ Vampires will be friends forever ∮
∮ 吸血鬼也永远都是好朋友 ∮
∮ Literally ∮
∮ 永永远远 ∮
∮ Forever ∮
∮ 在一起 ∮
Great job，vampires。Give yourselves a hug.
唱得真好 吸血鬼们 抱抱自己吧
We're going.
我们走
What？Where？
什么？去哪里？
（禁止入内）
Why are we doing this？
我们为什么要这样？
You'd rather be listening to those putrid new songs？
你难道更想去听那些无聊的新儿歌吗？
What happened to Michael Row Your Corpse Ashore？
「迈克尔把尸体送上岸」不是挺好的吗？
Or Old McWerewolf Had An Axe？
还有「老狼人和斧头」也不错啊？
We shouldn't be up here，Drac.
德古 我们不应该上来的
Who's ready to fly？
谁准备好要飞了？
Me！Me！Like a superhero.
我！我！我要像超人一样
Better！Like a vampire！
还有更好的！像吸血鬼一样！
This thing is rickety.
这座塔摇摇欲坠的
You know what？Maybe the kid isn't supposed to fly.
你知道吗？可能小孩子根本还不应该会飞呢
Quiet。This is how they learn.
别说了 小孩子们就应该这样
You throw them and they figure it out.
把他们扔下去自然就会飞了
It's how I was taught.
我就是这么学会的
I wanna fly now！
我现在就想飞！
Attabat。You know Papa's right here if you need him.
这就对了 你需要外公的时候 外公就会在你身边
Uh。I can't watch this.
天啊 我不敢看了
Please don't.
拜托 你别这样
Here we go！
飞吧！
He's still not flying.
他还没开始飞呢
He will.
他会的
Still not.
还是没有
It'll happen.
总能学会的
This is a tall tower.
这塔可够高的
That's why it's good.
所以才适合学习飞
You should get him.
你应该去救他了
He's gonna fall to his death.
他会摔死的
He's taking his time.
他可能学得比较慢吧
Drac！
德古！
I did that my first time.
我第一次的时候也是这样的
He's getting too close to the ground！
他离地面很近了！
You know what？He's not gonna fly.
说真的 他是学不会飞了！
I told you。Papa's always here for you.
我跟你说过了 外公一直陪在你身边
Again！Again！
再来一次！再来一次！
Oh，dear。Oh，my devil。We're gonna have to report this.
天啊 我的天啊 我们得上报这件事
You mean to the papers？
你是说要上报纸？
I guess it was pretty cool，but I'm not about getting press.
虽然这样是挺酷的 但我还不想惊动媒体
No，sir。I mean the authorities.
不是 先生 我是要向上级汇报
I can't not report child endangerment.
孩子们遇到的危险我不能隐瞒不报
Whoa！Listen to me。That was fun.
你给我听着 从上面飞下来是很好玩的事情
Your singing is child endangerment.
你唱的歌才是孩子们面临的危险
Should we go down and help him？
我们要不要下去帮帮他？
Nope。I told him this was nuts。He's on his own.
不去 我早就跟他说过这样太过分了 我才不去帮他
We have to call the boy's mother.
我们得把孩子的母亲叫来
No，that ain't happening.
不行 绝不可以
His mother's already nutsy koo koo！
他妈妈本来就已经疯疯癫癫的了！
I have to follow protocol.
我得按章办事
You will not follow protocol.
你不会按章办事的
I'm a vampire。I can't be hypnotized.
我也是吸血鬼 不会被催眠的
Right.
说得对
Now，please。Don't make me call the police.
好了 你别逼我叫警察来
No one's calling nobody！
你谁也别叫了 行不行！
Fire！
着火了！
Stop，drop and roll。Stop，drop and roll.
别跑了 停下来在地上打滚就行 别跑了
Screaming's not helping！
尖叫是没用的！
Are we bad guys，Papa Drac？
我们是坏人吗 德古外公？
Bad？
坏人？
No。You're the best kid in the world.
当然不是 你是这世界上最乖的小孩了
We didn't start the fire。It was the tower.
不是我们放的火 是塔的问题
That's a very unsafe tower.
那座塔早就年久失修了
You're lucky we don't call the authorities.
我们没向上级汇报你就偷着乐去吧
Let's go，my hero.
我们走吧 小英雄
Cebause I'm Batman！To the Batmobile！
应为我是蝙蝠侠！我们去坐蝙蝠车！
Yes。To the…
是啊 去坐…
Sorry about all that stuff。I guess they thought you'd like it.
对不起 让你失望了 我估计他们也是觉得你会喜欢才这样做的
Why do I feel so weird here？
为什么在这里我感觉这么别扭呢？
No，hon。They're being weird.
不 亲爱的 奇怪的是他们
I think they're just trying to help me.
他们只是想帮我
I mean，I grew up knowing nothing living inside that hotel.
我从小就在旅社长大 对外界一无所知
And you learned about everything growing up in Santa Claus.
而你在圣诞老人家长大 无所不知
Santa Cruz。But，uh…
是圣克鲁兹 不过…
Maybe if Dennis grows up away from Transylvania，
如果让丹尼斯在精灵旅社外面长大
he won't be so freaky。Like me.
他就不会像我一样 那么奇怪
Are you nuts？Mavis，you're a blast.
你疯了吗？梅菲斯 你很棒的
You're so full of life and curious about everything.
你总是充满活力和好奇心
If Dennis grows up to be just like you，
如果丹尼斯长大能像你一样
I'll be the luckiest dad in the world.
我就是世界上最幸运的爸爸了
I love you，Johnnystein.
我真爱你 约翰尼斯坦
You know what？
知道吗？
As long as we're all together，we'll be happy anywhere.
只要我们在一起 无论到哪里都很幸福
Even at the hotel.
哪怕是留在精灵旅社
Yes！
太好了！
What are you doing？
你在干什么？
Check out this video my friend sent me.
快看我朋友发来的视频
This kid is an awesome daredevil.
这孩子简直是超赞的不死神童
Oh，dude！
哥们！
Did you get it？
看到了吗？
Wait！Is that Dennis？
等一下！那是丹尼斯吗？
No！Is it？No。It's just hard to see。But…
不是！是吗？根本看不清楚 况且…
Oops。Just deleted it。So，it's gone.
糟糕 删掉了 看不到了
What？It's Mavis。I'm not answering it.
什么？是梅菲斯 我不会接的
Come on，Drac。You have to.
快点吧 德古 快接电话
All right！
好吧！
Yes，honeybunch.
是我 小宝贝
Dad？Where are you？
爸 你在哪里？
Um… we're outside the hotel having a little cookout.
我们在旅社外烧烤呢
It's perfectly safe.
绝对安全
What's that noise？Is that a siren？
什么声音？是火灾警报声吗？
Oh，those are just some wailing banshees checking in.
最近旅社住进来几个爱哭的怪物
Quiet，you banshees.
安静点 你们这群怪物
We're trying to have a perfectly safe cookout over here.
我们正打算举办一场绝对安全的野餐会
Mommy！I wanna say hi！Mommy！Mommy！
妈咪！我要打个招呼！妈咪！妈咪！
Papa Drac just tried to teach me how to fly.
德古外公刚才教我怎么飞行
Wait a minute。Is that the mother？
等一下 是他妈妈的电话吗？
Oh，no。Static again.
不好 又有干扰了
I am coming back to the hotel right now.
我这就回旅社
And you better be there or I swear，
我要是在旅社找不到你的话
Dad，you're gonna be very sorry.
爸爸 我一定会让你后悔的
What's goin' on？
怎么回事？
We need to get home right away.
我们得马上回家
Okay。I'll go wake up my backpack.
好吧 我这就去叫醒我的背包
Guys，we gotta move.
伙计们 我们得撤了
We got no car！How we gonna get out of here？
没有车！我们怎么离开这里啊？
Don't worry。I made a call.
别担心 我打了个电话
I'm sorry，Blobby。We really meant to call you sooner.
不好意思 布罗比 我们应该早点给你打电话的
Hit it！
出发！
Transylvania.
去精灵旅社
You want to go where？
你们要去哪里？
Transylvania。As soon as possible.
精灵旅社 最近的航班
We don't fly direct to Transylvania.
我们没有直达精灵旅社的航班
You don't？
没有？
You can go to Bucharest，but you'll have to
你可以先到布加勒斯特（罗马尼亚的首都）
switch planes in Chicago and then Zurich.
然后在芝加哥转机 再在苏黎世转机（瑞士北部城市）
So，when would we get there？
那什么时候才能到？
Well，the Chicago flight's delayed due to bad weather.
芝加哥的航班因为天气原因延迟了
So，two seats in coach？
你们要两张二等舱的机票吗？
No！
不要！
- No！- Yes.
- 不会吧！- 会的
You have to go now？When we finally have no traffic.
你非要现在去吗？我们好不容易不堵车了
You're killing me，Blobby.
你要折磨死我了 布罗比
I still have some cloud on me。Gotta do a selfie！
我头上还有云 好想自拍一张！
Johnny！Not now！
约翰尼！现在别拍！
Okay。Maybe later.
好吧 等会再说
This scooter thing's out of juice。We're never gonna make it.
这小摩托快没油了 我们怎么才能到啊
Frank，blow.
弗兰克 吹气
Now！
放手！
How fun is this？Why are you laughing？You like that？
有意思吧？你怎么这么开心啊？你喜欢吗？
Watch this.
看着
Coochie-coochie-coochie-coo！
咯吱 咯吱！
Now this is flying，Denisovich.
这就是飞行 丹尼索维奇
Like a vampire.
就像吸血鬼一样
That's my boy。Look at you go.
好孩子 看你飞得多好
You're the coolest guy who wears a cape，Papa Drac.
你是穿斗篷的人里面最帅的 德古外公
So，hey，when are you going to get here already？
你们什么时候到啊？
We've been waiting…
我们已经等了…
Give me my son.
把儿子给我
We just went out for some avocados.
我们刚才去吃牛油果了
Mommy！I flew！
妈咪！我会飞了！
I saw.
我看到了
∮ Mother's already nutsy koo koo ∮
∮ 妈妈已经疯疯癫癫 ∮
∮ Nutsy koo koo ∮
∮ 疯疯癫癫 ∮
∮ Koo koo Oh，dear。Oh，dear ∮
∮ 疯疯癫癫 宝贝 宝贝 ∮
∮ Oh，my devil I have to follow protocol ∮
∮ 小恶魔 我要按章办事 ∮
∮ That ain't happening That ain't happening ∮
∮ 绝不可以 绝不可以 ∮
∮ Mother's already ∮
∮ 妈妈已经 ∮
∮ Koo koo ∮
∮ 疯疯 ∮
∮ 颠颠 ∮
I was worried Dennis wasn't safe around other monsters.
本来我担心丹尼斯和其他怪物一起不安全
Now I don't even feel like he's safe around you.
现在我觉得他和你在一起也不安全
But I was just…
但我只是…
What was it you said？
你之前怎么说的？
Human，monster，unicorn。That it didn't matter？
无论他是人类 怪物 还是独角兽 都没关系？
Well，I just know his life would…
我只是觉得他…
We'll have his birthday party here on Wednesday.
周三我们在这里给他办生日宴
Then we're moving.
然后就离开这里
Please，Mavey。Don't leave.
求你了 梅菲 不要走
Maybe you've let humans into your hotel，Dad.
也许你让人类住进了旅社 爸爸
But I don't think you've let them into your heart.
但是在你心里 你并没有真正接受他们
I can do it。I can do it.
我可以的 我可以的
I'm a bat。I'm a bat.
我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠
I'm a bat。I'm a bat。I'm a bat！
我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠 我是蝙蝠！
Dennis？What are you doing，sweetie？
丹尼斯？你在干什么 宝贝？
Uh… nothing.
没什么
Careful。Let me help you down from there.
小心点 我抱你下来
Are you getting excited about your big party？
生日宴会马上到了 你激动吗？
I guess so.
是吧
You know who's coming？Daddy's whole family.
你猜谁要来？爸爸的家人都来
Grandpa Mike and Grandma Linda.
麦克爷爷 琳达奶奶
All your cousins and aunts and uncles who love you so much.
还有疼你的哥哥姐姐 叔叔阿姨
And then they're gonna be with us when we move to California.
然后我们会和他们一起回加利福尼亚
Mommy，are we going away because I'm not a monster？
妈咪 因为我不是怪物 所以我们必须搬走吗？
What？No。Dennis，of course not.
什么？不 丹尼斯 不是的
It's just grown-up stuff.
是因为你长大了
Okay。But what about Papa Drac？
好吧 那德古外公怎么办？
He's gonna be here all alone.
这里只剩下他一个了
Papa Drac has to stay here to run the hotel.
德古外公要留在这里经营旅社
But he'll visit us。And we'll visit him.
他会去看我们的 我们也会回来看他
Can we call him every night？
我们能每天晚上给他打电话吗？
Sure.
当然可以
Awesome！
太棒了！
Hello。We're here.
你好 我们来了
∮ The night brings Johnny's family here ∮
∮ 今夜约翰尼一家到来了 ∮
∮ To take away all that Drac holds dear ∮
∮ 他们要带走德古的心爱之物 ∮
Welcome，welcome.
欢迎 欢迎
∮ Hide your feelings ∮
∮ 埋葬你所有的情绪 ∮
∮ Keep them all inside ∮
∮ 让它们在内心发酵 ∮
Dude，why do you wanna leave？This place is out of control.
哥们 你为什么要走呢？这地方真是太棒了
I don't wanna leave.
我也不想走
All these awesome freakazoids！
看那些超赞的僵尸怪！
So，who's the coolest monster？
谁是最酷的怪物？
Kakie.
凯蒂
Kakie。What a wussbag.
凯蒂 真没出息
Isn't it nice to have the whole family together？
大家欢聚一堂多好啊？
Mavis，do you have any cousins or thingies in your family？
梅菲斯 你有兄弟或者姐妹吗？
No。It's just been me and Dad.
没有 我家只有我和我爸
I never did ask how you lost your mom.
我从来没问过你妈妈是怎么过世的
Oh。She was killed by angry humans.
她被愤怒的人类杀死了
∮ Awkward ∮
∮ 好尴尬 ∮
But there is my Grandpa Vlad.
但我有爷爷瓦拉德
Oh，you have a grandpa？
你有爷爷？
Yeah。He'll be at the party。I invited him.
是的 他会来参加宴会的 我邀请他了
You invited him？
你邀请他了？
Dad，he's never seen Dennis.
爸爸 他都没见过丹尼斯
I wanted them to meet once before we go.
我想在走之前让他们见一面
Sure。Great。Peachy。Good old Vlad.
当然了 太好了 和蔼老人家 瓦拉德
Anybody have a wet wipe？
有人有湿巾吗？
（精灵旅社 残酷山谷666号 瓦拉德收）
Holy rabies。He finally invites me to something.
我的老天狗啊 他终于邀请我了
He's got a grandkid？
他都有外孙了？
And he never told you？
他都没告诉你？
Easy，Bela。At least there's another vampire in the family.
冷静 贝拉 至少家族里多了一个吸血鬼
It's at a hotel？Fancy schmancy.
在旅社举行？够土豪嘛
Hotels are for humans！
旅社里都是人类！
Bela，shut your blood hole。Look what you started.
贝拉 闭上你的血盆大口 看看你干的好事
Don't worry，gang.
大家伙别担心
I raised my son to hate and kill and steal the souls of humans
我一直教育我儿子要杀戮 仇恨 窃取人类的灵魂
like a good boy.
那才是好孩子
Yes，Grandpa Vlad will be so happy when he sees
是的 如果瓦拉德爷爷看到
the big masquerade party Johnny and I have planned.
我和约翰尼策划的盛大的化装舞会 一定会非常开心的
What？
什么？
Play along。It's my dad.
配合一点 我爸要来
You have a dad？That's funny.
你有爸爸？挺有意思
Listen to me。My dad cannot know you're a human.
听我说 绝对不能让我爸知道你是人类
Or any of your family.
你全家都是人类
What？But，Drac，I'm proud that we're…
什么？但是 德古 我很自豪的…
Or he'll steal your family's souls and eat your backpack.
要是让他知道了 他就会窃取你家人的灵魂 吃掉你的背包
That's right，gang.
没错 各位
We're gonna make the birthday a monster masquerade party.
我们会把生日宴会办成怪物化装舞会
- Really？- Oh，that's lovely.
- 是吗？- 好主意
Sort of like a last hurrah
就算是丹尼斯回归
before Dennis gets to be with normal people.
正常人生活之前的最后一次狂欢
I couldn't have said it better.
说的真是太好了
（丹尼斯五岁生日派对）
What do you think，Mavis？
怎么样 梅菲斯？
I think I'm starting to like being creepy.
我觉得我已经喜欢上怪模怪样了
You're lucky we don't call the authorities.
我们没向上级汇报你就偷着乐去吧
Let's go，my hero.
我们走吧 小英雄
Because I'm Batman！
因为我是蝙蝠侠！
Yes！To the Batmobile！
对！我们去坐蝙蝠车！
Got your butt kicked by a girl，Batman.
你被女孩子欺负了 蝙蝠侠
Yeah。Whatever。I'm not about to cry.
随便吧 我不会哭的
Hotel Transylvania.
精灵旅社
I smell humans！
我闻到了人类的味道！
Tear it down！
统统撕碎！
Bela，we're in the outside world。You're gonna smell humans.
贝拉 我们来到外面的世界 当然有人类的味道
You know what？Just wait outside for me。This is family stuff.
听我说 你在外面等我 这是我的家事
You'll only get in the way.
你去了只会捣乱
I just wanna meet the little fanger.
我只想见见那个小家伙
He should know his great-vampa.
他应该认识他伟大的吸祖爷
His what？
吸什么？
Vampire grandpa。Come on。That was obvious.
吸血鬼祖爷爷 拜托 这都听不懂吗
Amazing party！
这宴会真棒！
So，what do you think？
你觉得怎么样？
This is your vampire costume？What are you，nuts？
这就是你的吸血鬼衣服？你是傻子吗？
I ordered it online.
我在淘宝买的
It was the only place that delivered overnight.
只有他家可以连夜发顺丰快递
You look like you got a baboon's butt on your head.
你的头上像是装了个狒狒的屁股
Have you at least practiced your voice？
你就不能练练说话吗？
You can't just talk like a hippie.
你不能一口嬉皮腔
I'm not a hippie。I'm a slacker.
我不是嬉皮 是懒鬼
Talk like a vampire.
像吸血鬼那样说话
My name is Count Jonafang。I am a vampire.
吾名尖牙约翰伯爵 我是吸血鬼
Okay，vampires don't go around saying，「I am a vampire.」
好了 吸血鬼才不会四处招摇 「我是吸血鬼」
Sorry。I am Count Jonafang。Bleh，bleh-bleh.
抱歉 吾名尖牙约翰伯爵
Are you kidding me？
你在耍我吗？
I'm sorry。I'm nervous.
对不起 我太紧张了
Yeah，listen，if you think I don't like it，
听着 如果你觉得我都不喜欢
you definitely don't want to say，
那你千万别在我爸面前说
「Bleh，bleh-bleh，」 in front of my father.
「巴拉 巴拉 巴拉」
Sir，Master Kakie has arrived.
先生 凯蒂大师来了
Drac，this is Brandon，a.k.a。Kakie.
德古 这是布兰登 大家都叫他凯蒂
- We got him for Dennis。- Hey，man.
- 我们特意请他来给丹尼斯表演 - 你好 伙计
Nauseated to meet you.
见到你真恶心
When does this happen？I got a book fair in half an hour.
什么时候开始？半小时后我还要去参加图书义卖呢
All right。Where's my vampson？
好了 我的吸孙在哪？
Oh，please。Still has to make a dramatic entrance.
拜托 非得这么作秀似的出场吗
Dad！Look at you！
爸爸！你可真精神啊！
So you run a hotel now？
你现在开旅社了？
From Prince of Darkness to King of Room Service.
黑暗王子摇身一变成了客服国王
Yes。So good to see you.
是啊 见到你真高兴
I'll be right with you.
我一会就来
Keep Vlad away from the humans and Mavis.
别让瓦拉德靠近人类和梅菲斯
I'm on it.
好的
Oh，now that is a neat costume.
你这身装扮真不赖
These two smell funny.
这两个闻起来很有意思
Oh，you're European.
你是欧洲人吧
It's called deodorant.
这叫体香剂
Nothing like insulting an entire continent，Linda.
你也别侮辱了整个大陆 琳达
Hey，Count！How goes it？Frankenstein.
伯爵！最近过得怎么样啊？我叫弗兰肯斯坦
Actually，I'm technically Frankenstein's monster.
严格来说 其实我是弗兰肯斯坦的怪物
Frankenstein，he's the doctor who…
弗兰肯斯坦 他是一个医生…
Would love to hear more。Call my people.
以后再说吧 把我家人叫来
So，let me introduce you to some of your son's other buddies.
我来给你介绍下你儿子的其他朋友
This is Murray.
这是墨瑞
Please don't kill me！
不要杀我！
I mean，yo，V！What's up？
我是说 哟 V！最近怎样啊？
Talking toilet paper。Well，that's a new one.
会说话的厕纸 这挺新鲜的
All right！Where's the kid？That's who I wanna meet.
好了！孩子在哪里？我想要见他
Johnny！
约翰尼！
This is Dracula's son-in-law.
这是德古拉的女婿
I am Count Jonafang.
我是尖牙约翰伯爵
Bleh，bleh，black sheep.
巴拉 巴拉 大黑羊
Have you any wool？
你有羊毛吗？
What's that thing on your head？
你头上是什么东西？
Looks like my grandmother's boobies.
看着像是我奶奶的胸部
Daddy，who's the man with the funny face？
爸爸 那个长得很搞笑的人是谁？
Is this the kid？
这就是我的曾孙了？
It sure is.
没错
Let me see those fangs.
让我看看那些尖牙
What are you doin'？
你在做什么？
Oh，I just love him so much.
我只是太爱他了
I want to hug him right in the fangs that he has.
我想要正对着他的尖牙抱着他
I repeat，let me see those fangs.
我再说一遍 让我看看那些尖牙
Oh，he's a late fanger，just like you.
他的尖牙长得比较慢 就像你一样
Yes。Yes。Just like me.
对 就像我一样
The big shot here was a little crybaby，all right.
这个大人物以前是一个爱哭鬼
Yes，yes，I was.
是 以前是
Used to pee in his bed.
还尿床
Okay，Dad.
好了 爸爸
We just need to scare the fangs out of the kid.
我们只要吓唬吓唬他 尖牙就长出来了
Hare ha hangs？
吓出尖牙？
Yeah，it's what I did for Mr。Tough Guy here.
没错 这个硬汉的尖牙就是我吓唬出来的
First，you've got to possess something
首先 你要控制住一样尖牙长得慢的人
the late fanger finds sweet and innocent.
觉得很亲切很无辜的东西
Then you show them what's what and…
然后你就像这样 然后…
Pop！
砰！
Trust me。It'll scare the fangs right out。Right，Drac？
相信我 这样就能把尖牙吓出来 对吧 德古？
Seriously，guys，if I'm late for the book fair，
说真的 伙计们 如果图书义卖迟到了
I'll miss the street fair.
那我就赶不上集市了
That's your guy.
就是他了
Possessed？But Dennis will be so upset.
要控制住他？但是丹尼斯会很伤心的
Don't you get it？This is our ticket.
你没听明白吗？这是我们的通行证
If it works for Denisovich，boom！He's a vampire.
如果能成功的话 砰！丹尼索维奇就变成吸血鬼了
And you all get to stay here.
你们就都能住在这里了
All right。All right.
好吧 好吧
- Capisce。- Good call.
- 明白了 - 很好
Kids，everyone，have a seat.
孩子们 大家请坐
Dennis has a big surprise for you.
丹尼斯给你们准备了一个惊喜
The one and only Kakie，The Cake Monster！
独一无二的凯蒂 「蛋糕怪物」！
Hey，kids！It's me，Kakie！
孩子们！我是凯蒂！
What a wonderful Kakie day it is！
多么美好的凯蒂的一天啊！
Now，I have a question。Who here loves cake？
现在 我有个问题 谁喜欢蛋糕啊？
Rise！
升！
Why am I floating？Can I have the stage manager，please？
我怎么飘起来了？舞台监督能来一下吗？
This isn't working for me.
我动不了了
Scary，Denisovich？You feeling anything？Any change？
害怕了吗 丹尼索维奇？有没感觉到什么？有没有什么变化？
Is Kakie okay？
凯蒂没事吧？
I want all the cake。Sharing is for cowards.
我要全部的蛋糕 懦夫才和别人分享
I don't remember any of this from the TV show.
我不记得在电视里看过这些
Um… I think I saw it on a Blu-Ray disc，bonus stuff.
我记得在蓝光碟里看过 是附加内容
Wait，why is Grandpa Vlad up there？
等等 瓦拉德爷爷怎么在那里？
I'm scared，Papa。What's happening to Kakie？
外公 我好怕 凯蒂怎么了？
You don't eat cake。Cake eat you！
不是你吃蛋糕 而是蛋糕吃你！
No！
不要！
Stop it！
够了！
What just happened，man？I'm outta here.
出什么事了？我要走了
None of these parents better review this on Yelp.
这些家长最好都别上大众点评评论
Hey，what did you just do？
你做什么？
A few more seconds
再过几秒钟
and the kid's fangs would have popped right out.
孩子的尖牙可能就长出来了
I don't care。It's not worth it.
我不在乎 这不值得
What's not worth it？
什么不值得？
It was my last attempt to make the boy a vampire，
这是我最后一次尝试让孩子变成吸血鬼
so you'd stay.
让你留下
By ruining his favorite thing？How could you do that？
为了这个 你就毁了他最爱的东西？你怎么可以这样？
We were desperate.
我们已经绝望了
You were in on this？
你也跟他是一伙的？
Dennis won't be happy in my town.
丹尼斯在我的家乡不会快乐的
Dennis hasn't been there.
丹尼斯根本就没去过那里
∮ Now husband and wife ∮
∮ 此时夫妻 ∮
∮ Feel the strain and the strife ∮
∮ 剑拔弩张 冲突爆发 ∮
Shut up！
闭嘴！
Johnny，Dennis is not a monster.
约翰尼 丹尼斯不是怪物
He likes avocado.
他喜欢牛油果
'Cause you don't let him eat anything fun.
因为你不让他吃别的好东西
I think Dennis just wants to be normal.
我想丹尼斯只想成为正常人
Can we stop using the word 「normal」？
能不说「正常」这个词吗？
Where we live now，he's normal.
在我们住的地方 他就是正常的
He is who he is。And you can't change him，Dad.
他就是他 你不能改变他 爸爸
Dennis，where are you going？
丹尼斯 你要去哪里？
Away.
我要离开这里
But it's not safe out here by yourself.
但是你自己在外面很危险
I know a place where we can hide。Follow me.
我知道一个地方 我们可以躲在那里 跟着我
If you didn't stop me，
如果你没阻止我
my great-grandson wouldn't have to be a wimp his whole life
我的曾孙就不会像这里的小邋遢一样
like Schlumpy over here.
一辈子都是懦弱的人
- A wimp？- Johnny，be cool.
- 懦弱的人？- 约翰尼 冷静
You wanna throw down，old man？
老人家 你想被干翻吗？
Certified yellow belt since 1997.
我1997年可就获得了黄带认证
No！
不！
What's this now？You're not a vampire？
这又怎么回事？你不是吸血鬼？
Bleh？
巴拉？
Of course he's human。He's our son。You think we're monsters？
他当然是人类了 他是我们的儿子 你以为我们是怪物吗？
You！You let your daughter marry a human and have a human kid？
你！你竟然让你女儿嫁给了人类 还生了个人类的孩子？
Why don't you just put a stake through my heart.
你干脆拿棍子刺穿我的心脏好了
We don't hate humans anymore，and they don't hate us.
我们不再厌恶人类了 他们也不讨厌我们
Humans？
人类？
You're a fool.
你这个傻瓜
Your great-grandson is the sweetest，kindest，
你的曾孙是我见过的最贴心 最善良
most special boy I've ever met.
最特别的男孩
And if you can't give him the love
如果因为他有一半人类的血液
he deserves because he's half-human，
你就不能给他应有的疼爱
then you're the fool.
那你才是个傻瓜
Oh，Daddy.
爸爸
Hey，where is Dennis？Dennis！
丹尼斯哪里去了？丹尼斯！
Dennis？
丹尼斯？
Happy birthday，Dennis。I made you a treat.
生日快乐 丹尼斯 我给你做了点吃的
- Dead pigeon？- Enjoy it.
- 死鸽子？- 吃吧
'Cause once I graduate business school
因为我一旦从商学院毕业
and start running a company，
经营公司以后
you're not gonna get home-cooked meals like this anymore.
你就再也吃不到这种家常便饭了
I have to move away，Winnie。To California.
我必须要搬走 温妮 搬到加利福利亚
My mommy thinks I'm not happy here
我妈妈觉得我在这里不开心
cebause I don't have hair on my face like you.
应为我脸上没有你那样的毛
I'm sorry I'm not a monster.
很抱歉 我不是个怪物
No，you are perfect。You're the nicest boy I know.
不 你很完美 你是我认识的最好的男孩
And I have 300 brothers.
而且我还有300个兄弟
You're nice，too，Winnie.
你也很好 温妮
Well，well，well。The little human and his pet.
好啊 小男孩和他的宠物
- Dennis！- Denisovich！
- 丹尼斯！- 丹尼索维奇！
He's not in the room.
他不在房间
He's not by the pool.
他没在泳池旁
He's not in this pot of soup.
他也不在这个汤罐里
Where could he be？
他会在哪里呢？
I don't know why I ever invited you.
我不知道为什么会邀请你
Dennis！Dennis！
丹尼斯！丹尼斯！
Denisovich！
丹尼索维奇！
Dennis！
丹尼斯！
Stop squirming.
别乱动
Why are you doing this？
你为什么要这么做？
Because this is wrong.
因为这是错的
Why doesn't anybody get that？
为什么别人都不懂呢？
Humans don't belong with monsters.
人类不能和怪兽相处
You're wrong！
你才错了！
I am not！
我没错！
I am holding you hostage.
我要拿你们当人质
And me and my crew are gonna
我和手下们要把那个
tear that human-hugging hotel to shreds.
欢迎人类的旅社拆个稀巴烂
You can't.
你不能这么做
Really？Why not？
真的吗？为什么？
Cebause…
应为…
Cebause，why？
应为什么？
Cebause it will make Papa Drac sad.
应为这样德古外公会伤心的
Ooh… Sad。And what are you gonna do about it？
会伤心 那你打算怎么做？
I don't know.
我不知道
You know why you don't know？
你知道你为什么不知道吗？
Cebause you're just a weak little boy.
因为你只是一个柔弱的小男孩
What was that？
怎么回事？
Dennis，we're coming.
丹尼斯 我们来了
Are you okay，Winnie？
你还好吗 温妮？
Yes，my zing.
是的 我的挚爱
Dennis！There he is，right there.
丹尼斯！他在那里 就在那里
Dennis！Baby！
丹尼斯！宝贝！
My big boy！
我的大男孩！
Dennis，we were lookin' for ya.
丹尼斯 我们都在找你
Sweetheart.
我的甜心
I'm so happy to see you.
很高兴见到你
There's his mean friends.
他的坏朋友来了
Oh… This'll be fun.
这下好玩了
I didn't do that.
不是我干的
You rock，Dennis.
你太棒了 丹尼斯
He means Denisovich.
他是说丹尼索维奇
Kakie rules！
凯蒂太厉害了！
Dennis，I'm coming。Whoa…
丹尼斯 我来了
I knew all that practice would pay off.
我就知道付出总有收获的
That's right，you better fly away.
没错 你们最好赶紧飞走
Papa Drac，I'm a vampire and a superhero.
德古外公 我是一只吸血鬼 也是一个超级英雄
Am I cool now？
我现在很酷吧？
「Now」？Dennis，you were always cool.
何止是现在？丹尼斯 你一直都很酷
Human，vampire，unicorn，you're perfect no matter what.
不管你是人类 吸血鬼 还是独角兽 你在我心中都是完美的
But since I'm a vampire，can we stay here？
既然我是一个吸血鬼 那我们可以待在这里吗？
Yes.
可以
All right！Yeah！
太棒了！
All right！
太赞了！
But you have to know，
但你们要知道
we're going to visit you here every holiday.
每个假期我们都会来看你们
- That's fine。- That's fine.
- 很好 - 很好
Don't ever come near me or my family again.
以后休想靠近我和我的家人
No！
不要！
Daddy，you just saved a human.
爸爸 你刚救了一个人类
All this pressure about
都是迫于压力啊
when the boy's fangs were coming out.
担心这孩子的尖牙什么时候长出来
Who cares？Mine came out years ago！Look.
谁在乎呢？我的牙几年前就掉了！看
Okay，Dad，put 'em back in before we all barf.
好了 爸爸 趁我们还没吐 赶紧放回去吧
Hey！Isn't it still somebody's birthday？
好像现在还是某人的生日吧？
Let me hear you sing！
大家一起唱吧！
I didn't do that.
不是我干的